#### Contact

606818422 (Work) masalinas.gancedo@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/masalinas (LinkedIn)

www.thingtrack.com (Company) www.konekti.org (Personal) www.kbuilding.es (Company)

## Top Skills

Java Enterprise Edition
Project Management
Microsoft SQL Server

### Languages

ingles (Full Professional)
Español (Native or Bilingual)

#### Certifications

Vaadin 7 Certified Developer

Active node-red contributor

Técnico Superior en Prevencion de Riesgos Laborales

OSGi Alliance Supporter

Vaadin Bluemix

#### Honors-Awards

Virgo Powered Product

DeepHealth Pneuma Saturdays.Al 2020 Winner

#### **Publications**

Konekti

# Miguel Angel Salinas Gancedo

Frontend Architect en Dentsu International

Greater Gijón Metropolitan Area

# Summary

Full-Stack Software Architect with high DevOps knowledge and an active IT Trainer on Pivotal, Kubernetes/Docker, Machine Learning, IoT or Blockchain. Industry 4.0 expert on techs like J2EE, NodeJS, .NET, Angular or Vaadin Certified, with excellent communication skills and a strong focus on building enterprise web systems for the industry.

I have been involved in the analysis and implementation of IT solution that have made the industry 4.0 possible in several organizations around the world.

#### My interests are:

- Manage software development teams.
- Logistics and Software training.
- Cryptocurrencies and Blockchain techs.
- Cloud Infraestructures and DevOps tools
- Trading and Stock Markets

#### My trainings covers:

- IBM Cloud: API Connect, Node-Red, Blockchain Hyperledger.
- Pivotal Cloud Foundry: Operator and Developer
- Docker and Kubernetes.
- Vertica BigData Analytics.
- Logistic Supply Chain Management: Warehouse and Management

#### My technical experience:

- Analyst and Software Architect in J2EE
- Deep Learning with Google TensorFlow
- Server-side Architect: Spring, NodeJS or IBM StrongLoop (API Connect).
- Client-side Architect: Vaadin, Angular, BootStrap or Google Material.

- Middleware Solutions: Node-red, Apache ActiveMQ, Apache Camel, Apache Kafka, Socket.Io, Mosquitto.
- High availability System: IBM Cloud-Foundry or Kubernetes
- Cloud Systems: Amazon AWS, Eucalyptus or IBM Bluemix, Google Cloud
- Microservices Architectures: Docker and Kubernetes.
- Desktop C# Architect: Hibernate, Castle Framework DI.
- Mobile Development: Windows CE, Ionic or Phonegap (Cordova).
- Expert in Linux (Red-Hat, Ubuntu) more than 15 years of experience.
- M2M Systems: Sensory Networks, Digi, Arduino, Raspberry Pi or Beaglebone devices. M2M communications with light protocols Stomp or MQTT.
- OSGi: modular web systems on Eclipse Virgo
- Logistic Systems: Warehouse, and Supply Chain Management System
- Electronic Hacker: Arduino, Raspberry, BeagleBone

# Experience

dentsu international
Freelance Full Stack Architect
September 2020 - Present (4 months)
Gijón, Principado de Asturias, España

Edikal Technology Co-Founder & CTO February 2012 - Present (8 years 11 months) Gijón y alrededores, España

Engineering and technical consultant

www.edikal.com

Thingtrack
Co-Founder & CTO
March 2011 - Present (9 years 10 months)
Gijón (Asturias)

Team leader and full-stack Architect.

Visit us in Thingtrack(www.thingtrack.com), Edikal(www.edikal.com) or our products like:

www.kbuilding.es www.glukose.net www.tachoexplorer.com

#### NTT Ltd.

Freelance Angular Frontend Architect April 2020 - July 2020 (4 months) Madrid, Comunidad de Madrid, España

**Angular Frontend Architect** 

Mecalux 5 years 1 month

Senior Logistic Software Architect March 2010 - March 2011 (1 year 1 month)

Training and logistic project supporter

Senior Software Project Manager March 2006 - March 2010 (4 years 1 month)

Logistics Project Manager, implementing information systems oriented to the automation and control of warehouse areas and distribution logistics.

Some of my clients:

- Hidrotarraco S.A
- Grupo Siro S.L
- Alimerka S.A
- Royal Surgerins S.L

Ibermática Software Project Manager February 2004 - 2006 (2 years)

Logistics Project Manager, implementing information systems oriented to the automation and control of production areas.

Some of my clients:

- AcerlorMittal S.A

- Kirchhoff Group: Automotive S.A
- European Engineering and Design Idesa S.A
- Fundición Nodular S.A
- Grupo Fagor Ederlan S.A
- Grupo Sarralle S.A

DF-Duro Felguera Software Project Manager June 2004 - December 2004 (7 months)

Parque Científico Tecnológico C/ Ada Byron, 90 33203 Gijón, Asturias (España)

Project Manager for the area of logistics automation software from Duro Felguera S.A. Planning and cost control

Some of my clients:

- Nireo Corporacion General S.A
- Serca S.A
- Fabrica Nacional de la Moneda y Timbre
- Rioglass Group S.A
- Savidiet S.L

thyssenkrupp

Software Project Engineering September 2001 - May 2004 (2 years 9 months)

Logistics Project Engineer, related to the automation of warehouses and distribution logistics.

Some of my clients are:

- Corporación Alimentaria Peñasanta (CAPSA) S.A
- Dadone S.A
- Renfe S.A

# Education

**EAE Business School** 

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Administración y gestión de empresas, general · (2016 - 2017)

Instituto BME (Bolsas y Mercados Españoles) - Grupo BME Curso de Bolsa y Derivados, Estudios de mercado · (2017 - 2017)

## Universidad de Oviedo

Técnico Superior en Prevención de Riesgos Laborales, Ergonomía, Seguridad e Higiene en el trabajo · (2003 - 2003)

#### Universidad de Oviedo

Industrial Engineering, Electronic and Computing · (1993 - 2000)